Parapsychology Laboratory Records, 1893-1984
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Research Files Series, 1912-1917and 1937-1963, 235 containers (117.5 lin. ft.)
  - Experimenter Files, 1912-1965
    - White, R.
      - Mayer color experiment, 1955 (Box 601)
      - Mendenhall experiment, 1955 (Box 601)
      - Pain motivation experiment, 1955 (Box 601)
      - 2nd pain experiment, 1955 (Box 601)
      - W. P. Smith experiment, 1955 (Box 602)
      - Swain data, 1955 (Box 602)
      - Teamwork experiment, 1955 (Box 602)
      - Testing, 1955 (Box 602)
      - Precognition experiment I, 1955 (Box 602)
      - Wiedemann experiments, 1955 (Box 602)
      - Multiple clairvoyance experiment, 1955-1956 (Box 602)
      - Nielsen tests, 1955-1956 (Box 602)
      - Pain experiment, 1955-1956 (Box 602)
      - Agnew experiment, 1956 (Box 602)
      - Experiment 1, 1956 (Box 602)
      - Experiment 2, 1956 (Box 602)
      - Miscellaneous, 1956 (Box 602)
      - Vesse PK experiments, 1958 (Box 602)
      - Dorm group test, undated (Box 602)
      - Dual agent test, undated (Box 602)
      - Symbol preference test, undated (Box 602)
      - PK with calculator, undated (Box 602)
    - Woodruff, J. Red-white cards series, 1940 (Box 602)
    - Unknown (Box 603)
      - Bell Adjustment Inventory (Box 603)
      - Experimental series, 1950, (7 folders) (Box 603)
      - Experimental series, 1950, (6 folders) (Box 604)
      - Experimental series, 1950, (4 folders) (Box 605)
      - Classroom ESP, 1959, (4 folders) (Box 605)
      - Telugu vs. English keys, c. 1964 (Box 605)
      - Analysis sheets, undated (Box 605)
      - Stewart data graph, undated (Box 605)
  - Miscellaneous, c. 1930-1950
    ESP cards, record sheets, and dice. Includes examples of hand-stamped cards, which were in use until 1937, and a pack of the first published cards, which were introduced that year. Arranged by type of material and then chronologically.
    - ESP cards, 1930-1950 (Box 606)
    - ESP record pad, 1950 (Box 606)
    - ESP record pad, 1950 (Box 606)
    - Pair of dice, undated (Box 606)
- J. B. Rhine Miscellaneous Files Series, 1925-1980, 48 containers.
  Largely Rhine's personal files, but including many general files relating to the Parapsychology Laboratory.
  - Personal Files, 1930-1979
    Chiefly personal correspondence, but including much documentation of the Duke Parapsychology Laboratory's relationship with University administration. Parallels the main Correspondence series. There are many subject files. Early files contain important legal documents, including wills. There is also a folder of Rhine's correspondence with C. G. Jung (1934-59). Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically, with the bulk of the correspondence grouped together in miscellaneous General correspondence folders.
    - 1930-1939,Legal Documents (Box 607)
    - 1933-1937,Personal finances, (5 folders) (Box 607)
    - 1934-1937,Laboratory finances, (2 folders) (Box 607)
    - 1934-1937,Laboratory finances, (2 folders) (Box 608)
    - 1934-1959,Correspondence with C.G. Jung (Box 608)
    - 1935-1936,“House notes” (Box 608)
    - 1935-1936, W.F. Prince Memorial Fund (Box 608)
    - 1936-1937
      - Family correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 608)
      - General correspondence (Box 608)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 608)
    - 1938-1940
      - Bills, (2 folders) (Box 608)
      - Books (Box 609)
      - Crunden-Cox correspondence (Box 609)
      - Extra-Sensory Perception After Sixty Years, (7 folders) (Box 609)
      - Family correspondence (Box 609)
      - Finances (Box 609)
      - General correspondence, (8 folders) (Box 610)
      - General correspondence (Box 611)
      - Gramaphone records (Box 611)
      - Greenwood, J.A. (Box 611)
      - Insurance (Box 611)
      - Lectures (Box 611)
      - McDougall, William (Box 611)
      - Manuscripts (Box 611)
      - Music (Box 611)
      - National affairs (Box 611)
      - Watt, Mary L. (Box 611)
      - Wauters, Bill (Box 611)
      - Weckesser, Miriam (Box 611)
      - Werber, Mrs. Charles (Box 611)
      - Whaley, Mrs. Randall (Box 611)
    - 1941-1945 (Box 612)
      - Bills, (2 folders) (Box 612)
      - Books (Box 612)
      - Charge sheets, (2 folders) (Box 612)
      - Crunden-Cox correspondence (Box 612)
      - Endowment program (Box 612)
      - Experiences (Box 612)
      - Fidelity Bank (Box 612)
      - General correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 612)
      - General correspondence, (6 folders) (Box 613)
      - General correspondence, (3 folders) (Box 614)
      - Gifts (Box 614)
      - Insurance (Box 614)
      - Interviews for magazines and newspapers (Box 614)
      - Lists (Box 614)
      - McMahan, C.H. (Box 614)
      - William McDougall Research Fund (Box 614)
      - McDougall, Kenneth (Box 614)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 614)
      - National affairs (Box 614)
      - Notes and Comments on Progress in ESP Research (Box 614)
      - Parapsychology Committee (Box 614)
      - Parapsychology Notes (Box 614)
      - Personal correspondence (Box 614)
      - Quotations, (2 folders) (Box 615)
      - Rhine family, (2 folders) (Box 615)
      - Rhine, Robbie (Box 615)
      - Royalties (Box 615)
      - Scientific Monthly reprints (Box 615)
      - Subscriptions to magazines (Box 615)
      - Taxes (Box 615)
      - Weckesser family (Box 615)
      - Whaley, Mrs. Randall (Box 615)
      - Work in progress (Box 615)
    - 1946-1948 (Box 616)
      - Bills (Box 616)
      - Books (Box 616)
      - Butler, George (Box 616)
      - General correspondence, (6 folders) (Box 616)
      - Insurance (Box 616)
      - McMahan, C.H. (Box 616)
      - Manuscripts, (3 folders) (Box 617)
      - Newcombe, Sylvia (Box 617)
      - Personal correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 617)
      - Subscriptions to magazines (Box 617)
      - Taxes (Box 617)
      - Weckesser family (Box 617)
      - Whaley, Mrs. Randall (Box 617)
    - 1949-1979
      - A miscellaneous (Box 617)
      - Applications, (2 folders) (Box 618)
      - B miscellaneous (Box 618)
      - Bills (Box 618)
      - Books (Box 618)
      - C miscellaneous (Box 618)
      - Cooperative Research Institute (Box 618)
      - D miscellaneous (Box 618)
      - Drugs (Box 618)
      - E miscellaneous (Box 619)
      - Editorials (Box 619)
      - F miscellaneous (Box 619)
      - Feather, Dr. and Mrs. Ben, (2 folders) (Box 619)
      - Feather, Dr. and Mrs. Ben (Box 619)
      - G miscellaneous (Box 619)
      - Giesen Management, (2 folders) (Box 619)
      - Gould, John M. (Box 619)
      - H miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 620)
      - Hawaiian trip (Box 620)
      - Honors certificates (Box 620)
      - I miscellaneous (Box 620)
      - Ideas and memos (Box 620)
      - Information expenditures (Box 620)
      - Insurance (Box 620)
      - J miscellaneous (Box 620)
      - K miscellaneous (Box 620)
      - L miscellaneous (Box 620)
      - Lecture bureaus (Box 620)
      - Life magazine (Box 620)
      - M miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 620)
      - McKenzie, Brian (Box 621)
      - Manuscripts, (3 folders) (Box 621)
      - N miscellaneous (Box 621)
      - Newcombe, Sylvia C. (Box 621)
      - O miscellaneous (Box 621)
      - Ozanne, Charles E. (Box 621)
      - Ozanne, Charles E., (2 folders) (Box 622)
      - P miscellaneous (Box 622)
      - Payments, (2 folders) (Box 622)
      - Q miscellaneous (Box 622)
      - R miscellaneous (Box 622)
      - References (Box 622)
      - Rhine family, (2 folders) (Box 622)
      - Rhine family, (7 folders) (Box 623)
      - S miscellaneous (Box 623)
      - S miscellaneous (Box 624)
      - T miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 624)
      - Taxes (Box 624)
      - U miscellaneous (Box 624)
      - V miscellaneous (Box 624)
      - W miscellaneous (Box 624)
      - Weckesserfamily (Box 624)
      - Whaley, Mrs. Randall (Box 624)
      - White, C.W. (Box 624)
      - X-Z miscellaneous (Box 624)
    - 1975-1979
      - Akers, Charles (Box 624)
      - Duke relations with FRNM (Box 624)
      - Grant applications (Box 624)
      - Hearing (Box 625)
      - Jahn, Robert G. (Box 625)
      - McDougall (Box 625)
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 625)
      - National Inquirer (Box 625)
      - Notes for talks, (3 folders) (Box 625)
      - Possible subjects (Box 625)
      - Rao, K.R. (Box 625)
      - Rockwell, Theodore (Box 625)
      - Psi Search (Box 625)
      - Smithsonian lecturee (Box 625)
      - Speech materials (Box 625)
      - Requests for aid (Box 625)
      - Texas Society for Psychical Research (Box 625)
  - FRNM Files, 1962-1978
    Files relating to the establishment of the Foundation for the Nature of Man in 1962, the transfer of the Parapsychology Laboratory to the Foundation as the Institute for Parapsychology in 1965, and other records of the Foundation. Arranged alphabetically.
    - Annual reports, 1972-1977 (Box 626)
    - Applications, 1965 (Box 626)
    - Architects, 1963 (Box 626)
    - Bevan, William, 1979 (Box 626)
    - Board of Advisors (RTC), 1964-1966 (Box 626)
    - Board of Directors, 1964-1981, (4 folders) (Box 626)
    - Clippings re Foundation, 1962-1965 (Box 626)
    - Employment policy, undated (Box 626)
    - Financial reports, 1967-1977 (Box 627)
    - Financial statements, 1966-1978 (Box 627)
    - Foundation Day, 1964 (Box 627)
    - Foundation material, 1962 (Box 627)
    - FRNM Bulletin, 1963 (Box 627)
    - Insurance, 1964-1965 (Box 627)
    - Location, 1965 (Box 627)
    - Mailing list, 1965 (Box 627)
    - Minutes of Board meetings, 1963 (Box 627)
    - Miscellaneous alphabetical files, 1962-1971 (Box 627)
    - News items, 1963-1966 (Box 627)
    - Newsmen, 1965 and undated (Box 627)
    - Notes on planning, 1965-1972 (Box 627)
    - Options, 1966 (Box 627)
    - Reports of Executive Director, 1964-1965 (Box 627)
    - Research Triangle Park, c. 1965 (Box 627)
    - Sales Tax, 1966 (Box 627)
    - Stone Foundation, undated (Box 627)
    - Stone Fund for Parapsychological Education, 1964-1965 (Box 627)
    - Trust Fund, 1976 (Box 627)
  - Special Files, 1925-1979
    Subject files, many of them biographical, several of them consisting of clippings. Arranged alphabetically.
    - Anpsi transfer files, c. 1950-1975, (10 folders) (Box 628)
    - Autobiographical notes, 1958-1964 (Box 628)
    - Book reviews, 1958-1970 (Box 628)
    - Bob Brier, 1970 (Box 628)
    - Diary of a schizophrenic, 1965-1969 (Box 628)
    - Dixon, Jeanne, 1969 (Box 629)
    - Dowsing clippings, 1944-1965 (Box 629)
    - Form letters, 1940 (Box 629)
    - Hurkos, Peter, 1962-1964 (Box 629)
    - Hypnotism, 1956-1975 (Box 629)
    - IPA symposium papers, 1959 (Box 629)
    - Journals and reprints, 1949-1960 (Box 629)
    - Jung, C.G., 1952-1961 (Box 629)
    - Laboratory procedures, c. 1955 (Box 629)
    - McDougall, William, 1937-1939 (Box 629)
    - Medical parapsychology (Box 629)
    - Miscellaneous, 1935-1978, (2 folders) (Box 629)
    - Ouija board clippings, 1967 (Box 629)
    - Parapschology reading course, 1963 (Box 629)
    - Paroptic vision clippings, 1964 (Box 630)
    - Plant experiments, 1959-1960 (Box 630)
    - Poetry and quotations, 1962 (Box 630)
    - Questionnaires, 1952 (Box 630)
    - Religion and parapsychology, 1944-1947 (Box 630)
    - Silva, José, 1972-1974, (2 folders) (Box 630)
    - Soviet articles on parapsychology, 1963-1969, (3 folders) (Box 630)
    - Swann, Ingo, 1977 (Box 630)
    - Test materials (Box 630)
    - Twins (Box 630)
    - Unusual stories (Box 630)
  - Academic Files, 1929-1948
    Records pertaining to Rhine's teaching, consisting mostly of lecture notes for courses. Arranged chronologically.
    - c. 1929,History of science notes (4 scrolls) (Box 631)
    - 1930,Survey of Science (Box 632)
    - 1930-1935,Class rolls (Box 632)
    - 1931
      - Logic (Box 632)
      - Psychology of Reasoning, (3 folders) (Box 632)
    - 1932
      - Psychology of Character, (3 folders) (Box 632)
      - Psychology of Character, (2 folders) (Box 633)
    - 1935,Psychology department (Box 633)
    - 1940,Case studies (Box 633)
    - 1941-1948
      - Psychology of Personality, (4 folders) (Box 633)
      - Psychology of Personality, (9 folders) (Box 634)
  - Manuscripts, 1928-1980
    Mostly clean copies and final drafts of Rhine's books and articles in non-technical publications, although a few technical papers are included in later files. Later files also include some notes and drafts of works in progress. There are two major unpublished manuscripts. The first is of a second technical book, dated ca. 1934-37. The second, The Development of Parapsychology, is based on a lecture given at the Smithsonian Institution in 1978. Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically.
    - 1928-1952,Duplicate manuscripts (Box 635)
    - 1929-1938
      - Unpublished manuscripts, (4 folders) (Box 635)
      - Unpublished manuscripts, (2 folders) (Box 636)
    - 1935-1938,Published manuscripts, (3 folders) (Box 636)
    - 1936?, second technical book, (2 folders) (Box 636)
    - 1937,New Frontiers of the Mind, (7 folders) (Box 637)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 638)
      - Published manuscripts, (2 folders) (Box 638)
      - Unpublished manuscripts, (2 folders) (Box 638)
    - 1940-1943
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts, (2 folders) (Box 638)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 639)
    - c. 1943,PK book manuscript (Box 639)
    - 1943-1947
      - The Reach of the Mind, (4 folders) (Box 639)
      - The Reach of the Mind, (6 folders) (Box 640)
      - The Reach of the Mind, (7 folders) (Box 641)
    - 1944-1946,Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 642)
    - 1950,Government (Box 642)
    - 1951-1961,Miscellaneous manuscripts, (5 folders) (Box 642)
    - 1952-1953
      - New World of the Mind (Box 642)
      - New World of the Mind, (15 folders) (Box 643)
      - New World of the Mind, (5 folders) (Box 644)
    - 1953,Parapsychology: Frontier Science of the Mind (Box 644)
    - 1953-1954,The natural science of the human spirit (Box 644)
    - 1953-1957,Miscellaneous manuscripts, (3 folders) (Box 645)
    - 1956-1957,Parapsychology: Frontier Science of the Mind, (2 folders) (Box 645)
    - 1957,Healing Survival (Box 645)
    - 1958,Reviews and comments on books (Box 646)
    - 1959
      - Education (Box 646)
      - Incorporeal personal agency (Box 646)
      - A new science for a new world crisis (Box 646)
      - On parapsychology and the nature of man (Box 646)
    - 1959-1962
      - Broadcast (Box 646)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 646)
    - 1960
      - Encyclopedia articles (Box 646)
      - Introduction to paperback Reach of the Mind (Box 646)
      - Parapsychology and the Future Progress of Mankind (Box 646)
    - 1962
      - Introduction to Extra-Sensory Perception (Box 646)
      - Science and the spiritual nature of man (Box 646)
    - 1963
      - ESP and the Nature of Man (Box 646)
      - Summer school lectures, (2 folders) (Box 646)
    - 1964
      - Foundation for Research on the Nature of Man (Box 646)
      - Parapsychology and human potentialities (Box 646)
      - Parapsychology and its revolutionary consequences (Box 646)
    - 1965 (Box 647)
      - BAAS lecture (Box 647)
      - Success article (Box 647)
    - 1968
      - Psychology and parapsychology (Box 647)
      - Psi missing (Box 647)
    - 1969
      - History of parapsychology (Box 647)
      - Man, Myth and Magic encyclopedia entry (Box 647)
    - 1969-1970,Parapsychology of religion (Box 647)
    - 1971,The importance of parapsychology to William McDougall (Box 647)
    - 1975,Miscellaneous manuscripts, (3 folders) (Box 647)
    - 1975-1976,Handbook of Parapsychology, (2 folders) (Box 648)
    - 1976
      - Miscellaneous (Box 648)
      - Parapsychology and the nature of man (Box 648)
      - Search for the nature of man (Box 648)
    - 1976-1977,Publication of chance results, (3 folders) (Box 648)
    - 1976-1978,Parapsychology and religion (Box 649)
    - 1977
      - Brief introduction to parapsychology (Box 649)
      - Notes for ASSR talk on parapsychology and religion (Box 649)
      - Forty years with Journal of Parapsychology (Box 649)
    - 1977-1980
      - Development of parapsychology, (4 folders) (Box 649)
      - Development of parapsychology, (6 folders) (Box 650)
    - 1978 (Box 651)
      - Development of parapsychology, (2 folders) (Box 651)
      - The beginnings of the Parapsychological Association (Box 651)
      - Parapsychology: Is it a science?, (2 folders) (Box 651)
      - Comments for Louie on Brian book (Box 651)
      - Letter to the Editor of Science (Box 651)
      - Commentary for The Elusive Science (Box 651)
      - My pardner, Gardner (Box 651)
    - 1980, SPR lecture (Box 651)
    - undated
      - Miscellaneous (Box 651)
      - Rhinebibliographies (Box 651)
  - Miscellaneous, 1937-1973
    Mostly materials relating to persons other than Rhine, although including some files of Rhine correspondence or writings that do not relate clearly to other series. Includes original questionnaires of the Clark and Warner survey of parapsychology in universities (1938) and a drafts of a dissertation by Frederick Dommeyer relating to parapsychology at Stanford University (c.1972). Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically.
    - 1927-1930,Clippings, (2 folders) (Box 652)
    - 1934,McDougall Foreword to Extra-Sensory Perception (Box 652)
    - 1934-1935,Clippings (Box 652)
    - 1935-1936,Early unpublished manuscripts (Box 652)
    - 1937,Manuscripts, (2 folders) (Box 652)
    - 1937-1938
      - Hale mediumistic communciations, (2 folders) (Box 652)
      - Hale mediumistic communications, (3 folders) (Box 653)
    - 1938,Clark and Werney survey, (3 folders) (Box 653)
    - 1949-1976
      - Katherine Banham parapsychology file (Box 653)
      - Katherine Banham parapsychology file (Box 654)
    - 1960-1979,Letters to Mary W. Fleig (Box 654)
    - 1961,Manczarski papers (Box 654)
    - 1965,Unanswered questions on Stanford University lecture (Box 654)
    - 1967,Outline of Parapsychology Reader (Box 654)
    - 1969,Brier and Tyminski paper on psi applications (Box 654)
    - c. 1972
      - Dommeyer manuscript re ESP at Stanford, (3 folders) (Box 654)
      - Dommeyer manuscript re ESP at Stanford, (3 folders) (Box 655)
    - 1973,Lowrie manuscript (Box 655)
    - undated
      - Booke? photos re exceptional feats (Box 655)
      - Cadoret paper on information theory (Box 655)
      - Miscellaneous items (Box 655)
      - U. Timm paper (Box 655)
- J. G. Pratt Miscellaneous Files Series, 1933-1963, 9 containers (4.5 lin. ft.)
  Personal and professional correspondence of J. G. Pratt, along with writings, lecture notes, and other material.
  - Correspondence, 1935-1963
    Personal and professional correspondence, and a few subject files.
    - 1935-1938, (6 folders) (Box 656)
    - 1938,Rasmussen precognition experiment (Box 656)
    - 1939
      - January - December (Box 656)
      - MacFarland, J.D. (Box 656)
    - 1940-1942, (3 folders) (Box 656)
    - 1943-1947, (5 folders) (Box 657)
    - 1948
      - General: A - Z (Box 657)
      - Reply to D. Parsons, (2 folders) (Box 657)
    - 1949
      - General: A - Z (Box 657)
      - Cadoret thesis (Box 657)
    - 1950
      - General: A - Z (Box 657)
      - Personal (Box 657)
    - 1951
      - General: A - Z (Box 657)
      - Personal (Box 657)
    - 1952,General: A - Z (Box 657)
    - 1953 (Box 658)
      - General: A - Z, (3 folders) (Box 658)
      - General: Homing clippings (Box 658)
      - General: ONR (Box 658)
    - 1954
      - General: A - M, (3 folders) (Box 658)
      - General: N - Z, (2 folders) (Box 659)
      - General: Kramer, Gustav (Box 659)
      - General: ONR (Box 659)
    - 1955
      - General: A - L, (4 folders) (Box 659)
      - General: M - Z, (4 folders) (Box 660)
      - General: Graue, L.C. (Box 660)
      - General: Homing conference (Box 660)
      - General: ONR (Box 660)
      - Personal (Box 660)
    - 1956
      - General: A - L, (2 folders) (Box 660)
      - General: M - Z, (3 folders) (Box 661)
      - General: Graue, L.C. (Box 661)
      - General: Greville, T.N.E. (Box 661)
      - General: Kramer, Gustav (Box 661)
      - General: Longman material (Box 661)
      - General: ONR (Box 661)
      - General: Pigeon reports (Box 661)
      - Personal (Box 661)
      - Personal: Andover correspondence (Box 661)
      - Personal: 31st class reunion (Box 661)
    - 1957 (Box 662)
      - General: A - Z, (3 folders) (Box 662)
      - General: Graue, L.C. (Box 662)
      - General: ONR (Box 662)
      - Personal (Box 662)
      - Personal: Vernon at Andover, (2 folders) (Box 662)
    - 1958
      - General: A - L, (2 folders) (Box 662)
      - General: M - Z (Box 663)
      - General: Edgar, William (Box 663)
      - Personal (Box 663)
      - Personal: Andover correspondence (Box 663)
      - Personal: Business (Box 663)
    - 1959
      - General: A - Z, (2 folders) (Box 663)
      - Personal (Box 663)
    - 1960,General: A - Z (Box 663)
    - 1961,General: A - Z (Box 663)
    - 1962
      - General: A - Z (Box 663)
      - General: Jobling, G.L. (Box 663)
      - General: Poppelman, Ray (Box 663)
      - General: Secretary's letters (Box 663)
    - 1963,General: A - Z (Box 663)
    - undated,Miscellaneous (Box 663)
  - Miscellaneous, 1933-1963
    Mostly relates to Pratt's writing, teaching, lectures, and travels. Also included are reports by W. G. Roll relating to the work of the Psychical Research Foundation.
    - 1933-1938,Manuscripts and speeches (Box 664)
    - 1934,Poems (Box 664)
    - 1939-1940,Psychology 101 (Box 664)
    - 1940
      - International Yearbook (Box 664)
      - Laboratory brochure (Box 664)
    - 1941?, ASPR paper (Box 664)
    - 1941
      - Parapsychology Notes (Box 664)
      - Personality course (Psychology 114) (Box 664)
    - 1949,Bibliography of publications (Box 664)
    - c. 1949,Training Program (Box 664)
    - 1953,Marsh thesis examination (Box 664)
    - 1956,New Jersey talk (Box 664)
    - 1957?,Notes on European trip (Box 664)
    - c. 1958,Duke campus photographs (Box 664)
    - 1960-1963, Psychical Research Foundation, (3 folders) (Box 664)
    - 1962, Foundation for Research on the Nature of Man (Box 664)
    - 1963,What this book is about (Box 664)
    - undated
      - Energies of Men course (Box 664)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 664)
      - Rose data analysis (Box 664)
      - Perception and meaning (Box 664)
      - Thought scraps (Box 664)
- Financial Papers Series, 1945-1962, 10 containers (5 lin. ft.)
  Records relating almost entirely to the period (1947-1963) when Pratt served as treasurer of the Parapsychology Laboratory. Included are files on grants from the Graduate Research Council and expenditures from the William McDougall Research Fund, which was set up to receive donations from outside sources, as well as general budget data, capital expenditures, office expenditures, and salaries. Other files relate to grants from the Rockefeller Foundation and the Office of Naval Research, which sponsored work of Pratt and others with homing pigeons. Two ledger books document transactions of the Journal of Parapsychology. Two folders contain records relating to Pratt's personal finances (1958-61). Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically.
  - 1945-1947 (Box 665)
    - Capital expenditures (Box 665)
    - Graduate Research Council grants (Box 665)
    - Ledger books (Box 665)
    - McDougall Research Fund (Box 665)
    - Office expenditures, (2 folders) (Box 665)
  - 1947-1953
    - Anpsi studies, (5 folders) (Box 665)
    - Check stubs (5 receipt books) (Box 666)
    - Budget data, (2 folders) (Box 667)
    - Capital expenditures (Box 667)
    - Graduate Research Council grants, (6 folders) (Box 667)
    - JP expenditures (2 ledger books) (Box 667)
    - Ledger book (Box 668)
    - McDougall Research Fund, (5 folders) (Box 668)